# VINEETH VIJAYAN

## Senior Web Developer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vineeethvijayan

Edappal, Malappuram, Kerala **9496 844 843** vineeth030@gmail.com

Full stack web developer with 5+ years of experience in designing, developing, testing and debugging Web apps. Have experience in all stages of development from preparing project quotes to delivery of project to client.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Laravel 5.5, Vuejs 2.0, Jquery 3.2, MySQL 5.7, PHP 7.0, Unit Testing, Git, Gulp, Forge, AWS, DigitalOcean.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **2Base Technologies**, Cochin — Module Lead

JUNE 2017 - PRESENT

Lead the development of different web apps and supported new devs in Laravel framework projects. Full stack development using Laravel, Jquery and MySQL.

## **SilverBloom Technologies**, Thrissur Infopark — Senior Web Developer

FEBRUARY 2015 - PRESENT

Developed different web apps and supported new devs in Laravel framework projects. Full stack development using Laravel, Vuejs, Jquery and MySQL

# **Esynergy Software Solutions**, Calicut — Web Developer

OCTOBER 2012 - FEBRUARY 2015

Lead the development and maintenance of their e-Learning web app. Developed using Core PHP, Jquery and MySQL.

# Esynergy Software Solutions, Calicut — C# Developer

JULY 2011 - OCTOBER 2012

Part of C# dev team for developing Powerpoint to HTML5 Converter Software. Development using Core PHP, Jquery and Javascript.

### **PROJECTS**

<u>Estherathi</u>, A booking website for enabling people to lease or rent short term lodgings like Wedding Halls, Resorts, Camps etc. Developed with Laravel, Jquery and MySQL. Deployed with Cloudways & Digitalocean.

<u>Karbala API</u>, A Laravel Rest API and admin dashboard for mobile application created for tourists visiting Karbala. Developed with Laravel and MySQL.

<u>Bubloos.com</u>, A job portal for freelance content writing buyers and sellers. Developed with Laravel, Vuejs, Jquery and MySQL. Payment Gateways used are Paypal & Stripe, Deployed with Forge & AWS.

<u>Officecares.com</u>, Showcase website for office products supplier with Algolia API search. Developed with Laravel, Vuejs, Jquery, MySQL. Deployed with Forge & Digitalocean.

<u>Parting.com</u>, A web portal for funeral homes in US with option to search by zip codes or city name. Developed with Laravel, Jquery, MySQL, Google Maps Geocoding API. Deployed with Heroku. Configured ShieldSquare & Mixpanel.

<u>IJvoice.com</u>, An art sharing website for children. There is option for children to upload their art works and teachers can approve them to be shown in the website. Developed with Laravel, Jquery and MySQL.

Zenler Online, An e-Learning web app for selling, buying and creating courses. Also trainer can track trainee progress and issue certificates. Developed with PHP, Jquery, AJAX and MySQL.

<u>Powerpoint to HTML5 Converter</u>, A desktop software for converting PPT to HTML5. Developed with C# and PowerPoint Object Model.

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Calicut,** VVIT Calicut — *B Tech in Computer Science*AUGUST 2008 - JUNE 2011